{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Can't Buy Me Love\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Twist and Shout\"","\"A Hard Day's Night\"","\"Help!\""],"question":"Which song became The Beatles' third No. 1 in a row in April 1964, with the lyrics \"I'll buy you a diamond ring, my friend\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Absolute Zero","incorrectAnswers":["Freezing Point","Mitchell's number","Equilibrium"],"question":"What is -459.7 F also know as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"I'm Gonna Be (500 Miles)","incorrectAnswers":["Puttin' on the Ritz","Unbelievable","I'm Too Sexy"],"question":"The Proclaimers had a one hit wonder in 1989 with which song?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Long March","incorrectAnswers":["The Great Retreat","The Red March","The Cultural Revolution"],"question":"What is the term for the 6,000-mile retreat begun by the Chinese Communist Army in 1934?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Marseille","incorrectAnswers":["Düsseldorf","Zürich","Dublin"],"question":"Which of these cities is in France?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Ice Hockey","incorrectAnswers":["Cycling","Soccer","Athletics"],"question":"Which sport is played at The Stanley Cup?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Pompeii","incorrectAnswers":["Genoa","Capua","Ostia"],"question":"Which Roman city was buried under volcanic ash from Mount Vesuvius In 79A.D.?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"De Militarized Zone","incorrectAnswers":["Definite Multivariate Zone","Deregulated Monetary Zone","Decompression Minimum Zone"],"question":"What does 'DMZ' stand for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Oliver McCall","incorrectAnswers":["Mike Tyson","Frank Bruno","Alex Brush"],"question":"Who was the first boxer to defeat Lennox Lewis in a professional bout?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Bluebirds","incorrectAnswers":["Cottagers","The Tykes","Wolves"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team Cardiff City?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Reese Witherspoon","incorrectAnswers":["Kristin Scott Thomas","Naomi Watts","Penélope Cruz"],"question":"Which actress has featured in both Little Nicky and Cruel Intentions?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"'Billie Jean' is a song by which musician?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"E. L. James","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Charles Dickens","Nick Hornby"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Fifty Shades of Grey'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"South Africa","incorrectAnswers":["Senegal","Democratic Republic of the Congo","Nigeria"],"question":"Durban is a city in which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Orange","Black","Maroon"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Iran?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Metropolis","incorrectAnswers":["The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring","The Lives of Others","The Departed"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'The son of a city's mastermind falls in love with a working-class prophet.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Joaquin Phoenix","incorrectAnswers":["Peter O'Toole","Roger Moore","Alan Cumming"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including Joker and Her?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Nicole Kidman","incorrectAnswers":["Natalie Portman","Kate Winslet","Maggie Smith"],"question":"Which actress has featured in films including Batman Forever and Moulin Rouge!?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cheese ","incorrectAnswers":["Bread","Fortified Wine","Confectionary"],"question":"What type of food is Port Salut?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Golf","incorrectAnswers":["Tennis","Cricket","Rugby"],"question":"With which sport is Jack Nicklaus associated ?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kingston","incorrectAnswers":["Bridgetown","Gaborone","Mogadishu"],"question":"What is the capital city of Jamaica?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lewis Carrol","incorrectAnswers":["Roald Dahl","TS Eliot","Oscar Wilde"],"question":"Who Wrote The Book 'Alice In Wonderland'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Port-au-Prince","incorrectAnswers":["Beirut","Bern","Georgetown"],"question":"What is the capital city of Haiti?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is used as a solvent for lacquer, floor polishes and resins.","incorrectAnswers":["It is used for surface purification, bleaching, odour removal and water disinfection.","It is used in manufacture of pulp and paper, alumina, soap and detergents.","It is used as oscillators in radios, watches."],"question":"What is the chemical trichloromethane often used for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Uzbekistan","United States","Benin"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Biryani?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"KNO3","incorrectAnswers":["D2O","KOH","NaOCI"],"question":"What is the chemical formula for potassium nitrate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oman","incorrectAnswers":["Qatar","Bahrain","Iran"],"question":"Which of these countries borders United Arab Emirates?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Speaker of the House","incorrectAnswers":["The Secretary of State","The Secretary of Defense","The Attorney General"],"question":"Which person becomes President of the USA if both the President and Vice President can no longer serve?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Japan","Thailand","Sri Lanka"],"question":"The Dharma Chakra or 'Wheel of Law' appears on the flag of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Club Med","incorrectAnswers":["Holiday Inn Resorts","Ski.com","Radisson Blu Resorts"],"question":"Philippe Bourguignon left the chairmanship of Eurodisney to join which group of resorts?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Madonna","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Nicki Minaj","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Who sung 'Material Girl'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Auschwitz","incorrectAnswers":["Dachau","Buchenwald","Bergen-Belsen"],"question":"Which of these was a Nazi concentration camp in Poland during World War 2?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mo'Nique","incorrectAnswers":["Penélope Cruz","Vera Farmiga","Maggie Gyllenhaal"],"question":"Who won the 2009 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Mary in Precious: Based on the Novel 'Push' by Sapphire?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Justin Bieber","incorrectAnswers":["Usher","Drake","Adele"],"question":"Which artist had a hit in 2016 with \"Love Yourself\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"George Harrison","incorrectAnswers":["Oasis","Paul Simon","Robbie Williams"],"question":"Whose Debut Solo Album Was Titled \"Wonderwall Music\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Rolls-Royce","incorrectAnswers":["Aston Martin","Toyota","Lamborghini"],"question":"Which car manufacturer names its models after different types of supernatural ghost-like beings?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Franklin Pierce","incorrectAnswers":["James Buchanan","John F. Kennedy","Jimmy Carter"],"question":"Who was the 14th president of the USA, in term during the period 1853–1857?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Sino-Tibetan","Turkic","Niger–Congo"],"question":"The language 'Greek' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Guimaraes","incorrectAnswers":["The Hague","Budapest","Milan"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Portugal?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Jason","incorrectAnswers":["Bartholomew","Phillip","Thaddeus"],"question":"Which of these was not one of Jesus's twelve apostles?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Japan","incorrectAnswers":["Vietnam","Russia","France"],"question":"In which country would you find the Itsukushima Shinto Shrine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Little Jack Horner","incorrectAnswers":["Hey Diddle Diddle","Mary Had a Little Lamb","Baa Baa Black Sheep"],"question":"What nursery rhyme is about a child who eats a Christmas pie?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Adolf Hitler","incorrectAnswers":["Benito Mussolini","Joseph Stalin","Winston Churchill"],"question":"Who was the leader of Nazi Germany during World War II?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Rubik's Cube","incorrectAnswers":["Furby","Playmobil","Hula Hoop"],"question":"Which toy is a multi-colored block you have to reorganize?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Futz","incorrectAnswers":["Discombobulate","Cabotage","Jentacular"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'to waste time or busy oneself aimlessly'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The preparation of books and manuscripts","incorrectAnswers":["Water","The nature and origins of knowledge","Microorganisms"],"question":"What is codicology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"X resembles the first letter of Christ in Greek","incorrectAnswers":["To avoid saying the name of Christ","To allow for the possibility that Christ didn't exist","To make the name more fun"],"question":"What is the origin of The X In 'Xmas'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"System of a Down","incorrectAnswers":["The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American metal band released the album 'Toxicity'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Spirit in the Sky","incorrectAnswers":["Relax","What's Up","Hot Child in the City"],"question":"What song did Norman Greenbaum have a hit with in 1969?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Jamaica ","incorrectAnswers":["India","Australia","France"],"question":"From Which Country Does The Beer 'Red Stripe' Originate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Harlem","incorrectAnswers":["Greenwich","Chelsea","Midtown"],"question":"What area of Manhattan precedes 'Shake' and 'Shuffle' in the names of dances?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A herd","incorrectAnswers":["A skulk","A run","A muster"],"question":"What is the word for a group of swans?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Maroon","Black","Orange"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Costa Rica?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1957","incorrectAnswers":["1941","1949","1965"],"question":"When was the first satellite sent into orbit?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Orion","incorrectAnswers":["Draco","Cassiopeia","Ursa Major"],"question":"Which constellation features Betelgeuse, the first star whose size was measured, in 1920?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Maginot Line","incorrectAnswers":["The Hadrian Wall","The de Galle Bunkers","The Vichy System"],"question":"What was the name of the defensive fortifications built by France along its border before World War 2?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bob Dylan","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Young","Eric Clapton","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American musician released the album 'Triplicate'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Perjury","incorrectAnswers":["Obstruction","Suborning","Fraud"],"question":"What is the term given to the act of lying in court?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Champagne ","incorrectAnswers":["Médoc","Saint-Émilion","Côtes du Rhône"],"question":"Which Famous Wine Region Is Centred On Reims?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Switzerland","incorrectAnswers":["Czechia","China","Japan"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.ch' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Adventures of Huckleberry Finn","incorrectAnswers":["Kidnapped","The Adventures of Tom Sawyer","A Connecticut Yankee in King Arthur's Court"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'You don’t know about me without you have read a book by the name of The Adventures of Tom Sawyer; but that ain't no matter.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Daft Punk","incorrectAnswers":["Gong","Indochine","Nouvelle Vague"],"question":"Which French electronica duo released the song 'Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Scrabble","incorrectAnswers":["Risk","Chess","Monopoly"],"question":"What is the name of the classic board game where players must spell words with tiles?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"New Delhi","incorrectAnswers":["Kolkata","Jaipur","Mumbai"],"question":"What is the capital city of India?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"a first-degree burn","incorrectAnswers":["a flesh wound","a contact burn","a cut"],"question":"What is the term used for a burn in which only the epidermis is affected?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Paul Simon","incorrectAnswers":["Elton John","Billy Joel","Bob Dylan"],"question":"Who won the Grammy Song of the Year award in 1970 for the song 'Bridge Over Troubled Water'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Walk Like An Egyptian","incorrectAnswers":["Dance Like A Zulu","Sway Like An Aztec","March Like A Roman"],"question":"Which of these is a song by The Bangles?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Vincent van Gogh","incorrectAnswers":["René Magritte","Édouard Manet","Gustave Courbet"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Starry Night\"","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Laos","incorrectAnswers":["Vietnam","Singapore","Bangladesh"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Thailand?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"It's Now or Never","incorrectAnswers":["Can't Help Falling in Love","Blue Suede Shoes","Jailhouse Rock"],"question":"Which Elvis Presley hit song was based on the Italian melody 'O Sole Mio'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Tequila Sunrise","incorrectAnswers":["Margaritaville","Whiskey in the Jar","Gin and Juice"],"question":"Which Eagles song mentions a mixed drink staring slowly across the sky?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"South Africa","incorrectAnswers":["Tanzania","Zambia","Zimbabwe"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.za' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Franz Kafka","incorrectAnswers":["Émile Zola","Nathaniel Hawthorne","Leo Tolstoy"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Country Doctor'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Catalyst","incorrectAnswers":["Precursor","Solvent","Base"],"question":"In dyeing what is the name given to the substance used for fixing the colour?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"the ecology of plant communities","incorrectAnswers":["schematic layouts","the interrelationship between an organism's physical functioning and its environment","the nature and origins of knowledge"],"question":"What is Phytosociology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Purgatorio","incorrectAnswers":["Paradiso","Commedia","Il Convivio"],"question":"What comes after 'Inferno' in Dante Alighieri's Divine Comedy trilogy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"How the environment interacts with an organism","incorrectAnswers":["The art of bell ringing","Bats","Redemption"],"question":"What is Ecophysiology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Stockholm","incorrectAnswers":["Prague","Barcelona","Madrid"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Sweden?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Chloroform","incorrectAnswers":["Table Salt","Saltpetre","Heavy water"],"question":"What is trichloromethane commonly known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sperm Whale","incorrectAnswers":["Anaconda","Silverback Gorilla","Tortoise"],"question":"From what animal is ambergris obtained?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephen King","incorrectAnswers":["H. P. Lovecraft","Edgar Allan Poe","Jack Vance"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Nightmares & Dreamscapes'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is used in nuclear reactors, as a neutron moderator.","incorrectAnswers":["It is commonly used as a condiment and food preservative.","It is used for surface purification, bleaching, odour removal and water disinfection.","It us used in baking to stabilize egg whites."],"question":"What is the chemical deuterium oxide often used for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The United Kingdom","incorrectAnswers":["Ukraine","Uzbekistan","Uganda"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.uk' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Axl Rose","incorrectAnswers":["Bob Dylan","Leonard Cohen","Slash"],"question":"William Bailey Is The Real Name Of Whch Singer?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Fourteen","incorrectAnswers":["Four","Six","Twelve"],"question":"How many lines are in a sonnet?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jules Verne","incorrectAnswers":["Victor Hugo","Alphonse Daudet","Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Mysterious Island'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Plate Tectonics ","incorrectAnswers":["Landslide","The Big Bang","Kercher's Theory"],"question":"Which Theory Is Used To Explain Continental Drift?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Billy Bob Thornton","incorrectAnswers":["Russell Crowe","Seth Rogen","John Turturro"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including Fargo and Armageddon?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The 17th century","incorrectAnswers":["The 16th century","The 18th century","The 19th century"],"question":"In which century did Rembrandt live?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Pan","incorrectAnswers":["Zeus","Artemis","Athena"],"question":"Which Greek god invented the shepherd's flute and had a musical contest with Apollo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Paul McCartney","George Michael"],"question":"Which British musician collaborated with Queen on the song 'Under Pressure'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Nine","incorrectAnswers":["One","Red","Blue"],"question":"What does the word 'neun' mean in German?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The League of Nations","incorrectAnswers":["G8","The Commonwealth of Nations","The Country Club"],"question":"What was the predecessor to the United Nations?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Cream","incorrectAnswers":["Jefferson Airplane","Stereolab","The Beatles"],"question":"Who Recorded The 1969 Album \"Goodbye\"? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"There are some things money can't buy","incorrectAnswers":["Everywhere you want to be","Because Change Happens","The World's Local Bank"],"question":"What is the marketing slogan of Mastercard?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Beyoncé","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Drake","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer, actress and record producer released the song 'Déjà Vu'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Philippines","incorrectAnswers":["Spain","Serbia","Taiwan"],"question":"Manila is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Uzbekistan","incorrectAnswers":["Guyana","Switzerland","Ghana"],"question":"Plov is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bottom Of South America ","incorrectAnswers":["Bottom of South Africa","East Coast of Africa","The West of Alaska"],"question":"Where Is Cape Horn?","difficulty":"medium"},